He called fire from heaven, then begged God to kill him. Same man, 24 hours later. This is the
story nobody expects when they hear the name Elijah. It started with a challenge. Israel had
abandoned God completely. King Ahab, Queen Jezebel, 450 prophets of Baal running the country. Elijah
stood up alone and said, let us settle this today. Two altars. Whoever sends fire is God.
The prophets of Baal went first. They prayed from morning until noon. Nothing. They cut
themselves. They screamed louder. Nothing. Elijah rebuilt the altar of God. He dug a trench around
it. Then he poured water over the sacrifice. Four jars, then four more, then four more again.
The wood was soaked. The trench was full. Then Elijah prayed. Fire came down from heaven. It
consumed everything. Wood, stone, water. 450 false prophets were executed that day.
And then Elijah prayed for rain. It had not rained in three years. It rained the greatest moment of his
life. And it destroyed him. Queen Jezebel heard what happened. She sent Elijah one message. By this
time tomorrow, you will be as dead as those prophets. That was it. One threat from one woman. And Elijah
ran. The man who stood against 450 alone ran into the desert by himself. He sat down under a juniper tree.
And he asked God to let him die. It is enough. I am no better than my fathers. Then he lay down and fell
asleep. An angel touched him. Get up and eat. There was bread freshly baked. A jar of water right there
in the desert. He ate. He drank. He lay down again. The angel came a second time. Get up and eat. The
journey is too great for you. No rebuke. Just food and rest. And get up when you are ready. Elijah walked
for 40 days to Mount Horeb. The mountain of God. He found a cave and slept inside it. And God asked him
a question. What are you doing here, Elijah? I am the only one left. I have done everything right and they
are trying to kill me. God told him to stand on the mountain. A wind came. So powerful it broke rocks
apart. God was not in the wind. An earthquake. God was not in the earthquake. Fire. God was not in the
fire and after the fire. A still small voice. Some translations say a gentle whisper. The same
question again. What are you doing here, Elijah? And this time God answered it. Go back. There is work
left. And you are not the only one left. There are 7,000 in Israel who have never bowed to Baal.
7,000. He thought he was alone. He was never alone. The greatest prophet in Israel's history had a
complete breakdown. And God's response was not disappointment. It was bread and water.
And a question asked gently, twice. Go read it tonight, 1 Kings, chapter 19.